And it's kind of quaint how you know, I
went to the first Quantified Self meet
up in
whatever it was 2008 or something with
12 people sitting around in Kevin
Kelly's house talking about
measuring things with Excel
spreadsheets. The world has changed. So,
there are armies of tens of thousands of
self-described biohackers and so on
talking about longevity. There's a lot
of nonsense. For yourself personally,
where have you landed in terms of
interventions or thinking about
interventions
for yourself?
>> I haven't done a ton. You know, it feels
like a lot collapses into like sleep
well, exercise a lot, you know, etc.
Like there's a handful of things that
kind of matter. Eat well.
>> Mhm.
>> And so, I've kind of collapsed on all
that stuff. I think there's one or two
things that maybe you can take that are
helpful and then there's some things I
always thought would be fun to
experiment with that I haven't done yet.
>> Like what?
>> I thought it'd be cool to try like a
rapamycin pulse or something.
>> Mhm.
>> So, stuff like that, but the reality is
that I'm kind of waiting for the real
drugs to come out and then maybe I'd use
those. Some of the ones that I actually
think will really impinge on longevity
or certain systems like we were talking
earlier about as you age, the muscle
that holds the lens of your eye weakens
and that's part of the reason that your
ability to focus kind of gets screwed up
and so
there should be eye drops for that. Like
there's a bunch of stuff around
neurosensory aging that I'd love to fund
to start up.
>> Mhm.
>> There's a bunch of stuff around the
cosmetics of aging that I've long been
talking about trying to find to actually
fund it. I clinical trial at Stanford to
to work on that for example.
>> Mhm.
>> Cuz I think it's very under-messed in
and peptides to me is basically that.
I think a lot of these people are taking
peptides as like certain forms of
health, but also certain forms of
cosmetic applications like 5-HKCU and
melatonin and all these things are
basically cosmetic in nature.
>> You mentioned a handful of things that
seem helpful to take. Are those just the
big, you know, vitamin D or are we
talking about other things? What are
What are more on that short list?
>> Vitamin D and creatine.
>> Yeah, got it.
>> If you want to lift. I don't know what's
on your list. I mean, you've you about
this so much more than I have.
What do you take away or what are you
thinking about or
>> I'm much more conservative than I think
people would expect. You know, I've
played around with a lot of things in my
earlier days and a lot of it is very, I
would say, capped risk. If you're
experimenting as I was with first
generation Dexcom continuous glucose
monitors in 2008, right? They were or
2009, very unpleasant to wear.
>> Yeah. And I wasn't aware of any non-type
1 diabetics using them at the time.
>> But I wasn't using much in terms of,
let's just say, questionable gene
therapy, flying to other countries to
use something like a follistatin. Not to
throw it under the bus, but I feel like
the general heuristic of no biological
free lunch, I recognize it's very
simplistic, but it's pretty helpful. At
least it will aid you in avoiding a lot
of pitfalls, right? So, I mean, there
are things I'm experimenting with,
different forms of ketone esters and
salts, for instance. I think some could
be very, very interesting for
cerebral vasculature. And since I have
Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's, et
cetera in my family, including for
people who are APOE33, so there are
certainly many other risk factors. I'm
paying a lot of attention to that side
of things, you know, obeticholic I think
is one to keep an eye on that's not yet
ready for prime time, but rapamycin's
interesting. I do think rapamycin is
interesting with a lot of asterisks
because you can screw yourself up if you
don't know what you're doing.
And
I mean, if you're playing with any
immunosuppressant, I mean, you just have
to be very careful,
but
looking at combining that, for instance,
one of the experiments that I might do
is and I would have a cleaner read of
signal if I only did one intervention,
but real life is different from
>> Yeah.
>> waiting for
science sometimes.
>> Reboot.
>> So, possibly combining Norwegian 4 by 4
interval training with rapamycin pulsing
to look at volumetric changes, if any,
in the hippocampus and other areas.
Like, I think that's a pretty
interesting hypothesis we're testing.
But, otherwise, it's basic basic, right?
It's creatine. It's the vitamin D's.
Look, if you have methylation issues or
you're taking medication, as I am, like
omeprazole, which can inhibit magnesium
absorption and other things, like you
want to keep an eye on that. But, not
too fancy, you know, I think urolithin A
is pretty interesting.
>> Mhm.
>> The data keeps mounting on that. I do
have a keen interest in mitochondrial
health, so if there are things which
could also include
regular intermittent fasting and
occasional 3 to 7-day fasting, which
could be a fast-mimicking diet, most
recently for me, based on the input from
Dr. Dominic D'Agostino, trying to foster
autophagy and mitophagy with some
regularity, not all the time.
>> Sure.
>> I'm not trying to optimize for that all
the time.
>> One thing I've been wondering, so if you
look at, like, a computer
and often the key to fixing your laptop
or the key to fixing any system is you
just [__] reboot it, right?
>> Yeah.
>> You reload the system and it just works
magically. Is there like a equivalent of
that? Is it like going under for
anesthesia?
Is there some nerve freezing thing that
some people have been doing recently?
>> Oof. Yeah, I don't know.
Sounds scary. Oh, maybe stellate
ganglion block?
>> Yeah, that's it. The stellate ganglion
block.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I mean, the rebooting
Ah, man, I'm like letting out an exhale
because
I
there are some interesting options for
very specific use cases. It makes sense
conceptually. I mean, you're more
qualified to speak to this, but I would
say This is spending a lot of time
around neuroscientists, and I spend a
lot of my time in terms of information
intake reading
or doing my best. Fortunately, with AI
tools, it's become a lot easier.
Not just getting a synopsis, but
actually using it to help you
learn concepts that you can kind of
layer in some
rational sequence structure. But, I read
a lot of neuroscience stuff and a lot of
optical stuff. There's actually a
surprising amount of I mean, there's
maybe not so surprising like
very strong intersection there. So, if
you're looking at like PBM and like
photobiomodulation through the eyes, I
mean, you can do it transcranially as
well. I would give a note of caution for
that for folks, but the reboot side, I
would say for instance, and people have
experienced this to a lesser extent with
GLP-1 agonists.
If they take it for weight loss, maybe
they stop smoking or they cut back on
drinking or
they have these
kind of system-wide decreases or
increases in it in impulse control.
>> Yeah.
>> For someone who's saying opiate addict,
I think that
ibogaine, which
in the future may take the form of an
active metabolite or something like
that,
in flood dosing,
at least that's seems pretty necessary
at this point, relatively high doses
under medical supervision cuz you can
have fatal cardiac events.
Co-administration of magnesium seems to
help, but it's dangerous stuff. People
should be careful.
You can, and there are lots of people
historically who deserve a lot of credit
for this, like Howard Lotsof,
and his wife, but
opiate addicts can go through
flood dosing of ibogaine and come out,
and they're basically given a window
with which they
won't experience withdrawal symptoms,
physical withdrawal symptoms.
And I think there probably applications
to other things with ibogaine or
pharmacological interventions like
ibogaine. And some of the craziest
stuff, honestly, related to that
molecule is
the
and I'm skeptical of this simple
description but it's a reversal in brain
age. It so changes in the brain based on
MRIs. Nolan Williams, rest in peace, and
his lab looked at this pretty closely
pre- and post-dosing of ibogaine for
veterans with traumatic brain injury.
And some of that might be due to
something called glial derived
neurotrophic factor, right? People might
be familiar with like BDNF.
So, ibogaine is one interesting option.
Anesthesia, I've become a lot more
cautious with general anesthesia.
>> Yeah.
>> Like I just had surgery yesterday and I
opted for local anesthesia, which in
this case was not a big deal cuz it was
just you can see it. Like had something
cut out of my head.
But
coming back to the
and I'm going to riff for a second here,
but the
autism spectrum disorder and ADHD
example you were unpacking where you
talked about the incentives, they might
be in perverse incentives to diagnose.
Well,
I mean,
not to quote Munger, right? But it's
like follow the money, right?
And a lot of people are put under
general who really don't need to be put
under general, but it adds a very, very,
very huge
line item to the tab. And there are
people
who go under anesthesia and wake up and
do not retain
the same ability to recall memories and
so on. Like their personalities become
in some way destabilized. And the fact
of the matter is
that a lot of anesthesia is very poorly
understood. We know it works, but it's
very poorly understood. And I don't
think
a lot of people
realize, because why would they unless
they've
you know, just spending a lot of time
looking into this.
There are lots of medications that are
incredibly
well-known, commonly prescribed for
which the mechanisms of action are
really poorly understood, if they're
understood at all. You know, like we
know based on studies they appear to be
well tolerated. Like side effects
profiles include A through Z.
And it certainly seems to exert this
effect or have an impact on biomarker X.
But we don't actually [__] know how
it works, you know?
And there's just a lot of stuff that
falls into that bucket. And so I am
cautious with a lot of it. But to come
back to your question, I went off on a
bit of a TED Talk. The most interesting
reboot that I've seen and I don't I
don't want to really water it down to
like the dopaminergic system, because
there's a lot more to it. But I began, I
think more so than ibogaine itself shows
what is possible. And I I don't know if
that's limited to drugs. I am very
bullish, and there're going to be
fuck-ups, there're going to be some
sidebars that don't look so good. But
brain stimulation and bioelectric
medicine,
broadly speaking,
is one of the great next frontiers.
Certainly in treating what we might
consider psychiatric disorders.
But also for performance enhancement.
And
we're at a point kind of looking for
those external why now answers, right?
There are actually some really good
answers to why now for this as a field.
And I think people will be experimenting
a lot with this but without the use of
pills and potions and IVs and actually
non-invasive brain stimulation maybe
some invasive in the case of implants.
So that's a long answer but yeah that's
on what I'm thinking about and tracking.
I mean some of this stuff we'll see but
I think a lot of this stuff could be
outpatient procedure. You walk in you're
in there for an hour or two and then
you're out
so we'll see.